Welcome to the annual league meetings
here in Arizona. I am Tim Twinman joined
by Dan Campbell. Dan, thanks for taking
the time.
>> Yeah.
>> So, this is a fun time of year, right? I
mean, the new league year starts, you
get free agency, the draft is around the
corner, you guys already have guys
coming to visit. Did is this a fun time
when the roster just starts to come
together a little bit?
>> It is. It there's there's a there's it's
bittersweet from the time that it ends.
I'm just talking about the the uh
transformation that gets made on the
roster and it happens every year. Uh and
so you know you lose some guys you man
you you got really fond of that really
helped you out big time. We lost a lot
of those guys but then it's also kind of
a rebirth. You know you get an
opportunity to bring in some new fresh
guys from from other places that uh you
feel like fit you and they'll bring a
new kind of energy. So So that's
exciting. You know, you mentioned some
of those guys like the the glue pieces
like an Alexander Law, like a a K frame,
right? Those are tough losses. Those
have been guys that have been with you.
But I does it become a point in just
this roster turnover where some of the
young guys now have to step into those
roles and and is there an excitement
with kind of seeing how some of those
young guys like a Malcolm Rodriguez or
somebody else, how they step in and
become those core pieces who are those
next guys? Is that a fun part to kind of
see how that develops? It is a fun part
and really that that's what a lot of
this becomes too is you're you are you
know we're banking on those guys. We're
we're saying we believe those guys are
going to take the next step and we're
saying some of those guys uh not only uh
from a production player st but a
leadership standpoint now there there is
I mean Alex and uh you know Khalif and
and uh
>> you know and Decker and you know okay
well now the next line of got Jack
Campbell you know pane all these this is
your room now um just for an example so
that's exciting too and but That's the
That's the cycle of this league. That's
And and you've got to put those guys in
a position where they can become better
players, they can help you and leaders.
>> Let's talk about free agency a little
bit because um you know, you guys
obviously are a draft, develop, and
resign. And when you have the success
that you guys had with that early on,
there just becomes a point where it's
going to tax you financially a little
bit. And there's guys that you've
resigned, there's guys that you're going
to resign. And just talk about the
strategy when you have seven, eight Pro
Bowl caliber players, right? You know,
the your core guys just trying to build
and find the right pieces around that
core and just maybe some of the
constraints that comes with that, some
of the difficulties in in finding ways
to do that.
>> Well, it is it becomes different and and
you know when when it's a good thing.
It's a good thing. We we did what we
said we wanted to do, man. Our core is
going to be guys that we uh they were
homegrown. We found them and we they
they got into our program and they
became what we are and they're the ones
who hold the standards for the rest of
the team. So, we got the hard part.
>> Yeah,
>> we we got the hard part. Now, when you
when you sign a lot of those guys to a
contract or andor for most teams, you
sign a quarterback that takes up a lot
of the cap. We have a quarterback and
he's damn good and and that's great. But
then you you've got to be, you know,
man, we we got to hit on these free
agents. You know, you got to be much
more creative with what you do. They got
to be able to fit you. It's got to be
cost uh effective, costefficient as much
as possible because you just don't. Um
but that's part of the fun, too, is
finding those guys that fit. Um but
listen, I I we wouldn't have it any
other way. Brad, myself, this is exactly
what we said we were going to do. And uh
and like I said, we got the hard part.
I'm sure there are 15 to 20 other teams
that would, you know, be worrying about
getting, you know, seven Pro Bowl guys
that are under the age of 27 with a
quarterback. There's there's worse
things to deal with, right?
>> But let's talk about some of the free
agents. Kade Maze was was a guy that you
guys obviously targeted, you know,
pretty early on. Just how does he fit
what you guys do up front? Why was he
why was he key for you guys?
>> Yeah, we we liked Cade in this process.
We felt like he really uh has grown. I
mean, he, you know, he's only played the
the center in the NFL for, you know,
really two years, if you will. Uh, kind
of came into his own and just really
propelled himself, got better and
better. We felt like he had a heavy
anchor in there in pass pro. Uh, he can
fit into the combinations. We don't feel
like we're restricted run gamewise, like
ah, well, we can't run wide zone with
this. We feel like he can do he can do
everything, and we do feel like he
upgrades us from from where we were, and
that's important. So, that gives us a
pivotal piece in the middle. Uh it it it
gives us some stability.
>> Larry Borham, another guy up front.
Obviously the offensive line was a focus
for you guys. Just getting it back to
where you were 2023 20 24 levels. Larry
Borham, 38 starts in this league, I
believe. Is he a guy that that you guys
think can can come in and and and start
and and be a guy that that's that
caliber of player for you?
>> We we uh we like Larry a lot, you know,
and he was another guy we identified um
that was able to man, he can play swing
tackle. I thought he did a nice job at
Miami last year. you know, he started
for them at right tackle and and really
held his own and it was the best season
he's had, you know, overall and but has
continued to get better. So, he really
gives us flexibility between Yeah, if we
didn't believe that he was a guy that
could start, then um then we we wouldn't
do it. But we also know, all right, if
if if that's not quite it, he is a swing
tackle and can play jumbo tight end. He
gives us so much flexibility at at the
at a baseline. He gives us a floor and
uh we like him and uh you know we feel
like he fits us too.
>> DJ Warm is another guy just would you
identify with him a guy who's you know
got a lot of production in this league
Dan and has played a lot and you just
the snaps how he plays setting an edge
against the running. He just seems like
a guy that that fits what you guys do.
always liked Wanom. Uh, you know, we
played against him at Minnesota and so
that was when I I first uh me
personally, well, you could say all of
us. I mean, we when you go against that
guy twice a year and
>> um, you know, and he's part of that
Dline rotation when we're going through
there and it's like, man, this guy just
play he plays hard, he plays the run, he
can get an edge. Um, he he seems to
always be in position like just a smart
uh, football player that plays hard,
man. He's he's got versatility. Played
special teams also at at uh Minnesota.
So, we just felt like, man, this guy's a
good fit for us.
>> And then uh two guys uh Christian Izzy
and Roger McCreary. To me, they they
kind of remind me of like when when you
guys brought in a Meek, right, had
gotten a a chance to play and and start
and done some good things, but then kind
of just picked up a found found a right
fit, picked up a bigger role. What do
you see in in those two guys and just
how they fit your secondary? It seems
like they're chess pieces. Both guys can
do maybe a lot of different things.
>> Yep. Uh both of those guys, you know, we
we've liked from afar for a while, you
know. So Izzy, I mean, look, Izzy was uh
you know, we go out there when he's a
rookie at Tampa and he just wrecked
shop. I mean, he's given us fits. I
mean, he's an aggressive player. He had
to start at the nickel for them. And I
mean, he he is a menace. He's a menace.
He's aggressive. He's feisty. Uh he's
all over the field. And oh, and then by
the way, he goes back and plays safety.
and he's and he's a kick-ass special
teams player. It's like, okay, this guy
fits us. And so, he's kind of always
been on the radar. Some of these guys
you play against that uh you feel like
kind of get after you a little bit,
you're like, man, that guy, you know,
that could be one of our guys one day,
you know, so you keep tabs on them. And
so, sure enough, that worked out. McCra
is somebody that Brad and I and and and
Ray and everybody, we always kind of
like, man, uh coming out of the process,
the draft process, we like McCra coming
out of Auburn. So, we've kind of kept
tabs on him. We just think he's he's a
pretty crafty, savvy, smart football
player. Can play nickel, can go outside
if you need it. Um, but he's got some
versatility.
>> You know, last one for me, just remind
the fans, too, the first wave of free
agency obviously gets all the news, but
this thing isn't over yet, right? I
mean, you guys are obviously in in draft
mode, too, but there are a lot of phases
to this. And you guys aren't done
building this team through free agency
yet.
>> No, no. Free agency is just one piece of
this. And we we we are not done. I mean,
we we free agency is still going on and
uh and then we got the draft and then
you got free agency after the draft and
then you trades are available through,
you know, whatever that is. I don't
know, week four, five, six, I don't know
anymore. But the point is there's still
Oh, and the waiver wire after training
camp, which we found guys, you know,
that's how we found John Kaminsky four
years ago. So, there's so many things
that that you have at your disposal that
man, we are far from done.
>> Yeah. I appreciate it, Dan. Thanks for
taking the time.
>> All right. Thanks, Tim.